Contact

shawntelj@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/shawntel-joseph-081a566b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing
BLS
Acute Care

Honors-Awards
Daisy Award Noimnee
Hope and Will Award

Shawntel Joseph

Travel Nurse at Premier Healthcare Professionals Greater Atlanta Area

Summary

Travel Nurse with 12 years of experience. Has a progressive training background that includes solid curriculum development. Leads informative clinical trainings, conducts educational sessions instructing nursing teams on standard practices and procedures, as well as the use, safety and efficiency of medical devices.

Master of Nursing: Walden University, with an expected graduation date of 12/2019. Also possesses a B.S. of Nursing: Chamberlain College, 6/2011.

Certifications: Georgia Stroke Core Curriculum, Train-the-Trainer, BLS, PALS, and ACLS

Licensed in Georgia and Massachusetts

Has managed 20+ direct reports with budgetary responsibilities including inventory controls and staff scheduling, in addition to hiring of clinical staff members. Adheres to quality control measures and Joint Commission readiness.

Project Manager of Epic ASAP projects, specifically for upgrades which required clinical documentation of updates.

Nursing expertise on utilization review and case / disease management.

Supervises and assists with ancillary staff, and operates as a preceptor to new Registered Nurses.

Establishes and maintains learning assistance / college success programs with a history of student success while using Evidence Based Practices.

Nursing areas of concentration: Fundamentals, Medical-Surgical; Adult / Pediatrics, Obstetrics, Mental-Health, Acute Care, Pharmacological Math, Primary and Urgent Care, Telemetry, Stroke, and Leadership.

EPIC ASAP super user and member of the CHOICE council with Children's Healthcare of Atlanta

2016: Daisy Award Nominee (WellStar)

Page 1 of 3

2014: March of Dimes Nurse of the Year Finalist | 2014: AJC

Nurse of the Year Nominee

2011: Hope & Will Award (CHOA)

Areas of Expertise:

Assessments

Case Management / Auditing

Patient / Family Education EMR System

Nurse Education / Training

Facility / Hospital Standards

EKG Interpretation

Individualized Patient Care

Curriculum Development

Experience

Premier Healthcare Professionals

Travel Nurse

November 2019 - Present (8 months)

Atlanta

Accountable Healthcare Staffing

Travel RN

May 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Chamberlain College of Nursing

Visiting Professor

August 2015 - Present (4 years 11 months)

WellStar Health System

RN

June 2009 - Present (11 years 1 month)

MedPro Staffing

Travel RN

July 2017 - November 2019 (2 years 5 months)

PruittHealth

Case Manager

July 2016 - July 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Norcross, Georgia

Atlanta Pediatric Partners
Clinical Liaison / RN Clinical Lead
April 2014 - May 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Children's Healthcare of Atlanta
Assistant Nurse Manager
March 2005 - September 2014 (9 years 7 months)

Education

Walden University

Master's degree, Family Practice Nurse/Nursing · (2017 - 2020)

Chamberlain College of Nursing-Addison Campus BSN, Nursing Science · (2011)

Columbus Technical College
Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2007 - 2008)